24 chapter 25 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 25 Ruben
Smith Now I must say a little about Reuben Smith, who was left in charge of
the stables when York went to London. No one more thoroughly understood his
business than he did, and when he was all right there could not be a more faithful
or valuable man. He was gentle and very clever in his management of horses, and
could doct to them almost as well as a farer for he had lived two years with a
veterinary surgeon. He was a First Rate driver; he could take a for in hand or a
tandem as easily as a pair. He was a handsome man, a good scholar, and had very pleasant
manners. I believe everybody liked him; certainly the horses did. The only wonder
was that he should be in an UND situation and not in the place of a head
coach like York; but he had one great fault and that was the love of
drink. He was not like some men, always at it; he used to keep steady for weeks or
months together, and then he would break out and have a “bout” of it, as York called
it, and be a disgrace to himself, a terror to his wife, and a nuisance to all that
had to do with him. He was, however, so useful the two or three times York had
hushed the matter up and kept it from the 's knowledge; but one night, when
Reuben had to drive a party home from a ball he was so drunk that he could not
hold the rains and a gentleman of the party had to mount the box and drive the
ladies home. Of course, this could not be hidden, and Reuben was at once dismissed;
his poor wife and the little children had to turn out of the pretty cottage by
the park gate and go where they could. Old Max told me all this, for it
happened a good while ago; but shortly before Ginger and I came Smith had been
taken back again. York had interceded for him with the L who is very kind-hearted,
and the man had promised faithfully that he would never taste another drop as
long as he lived there. He had kept his promise so well that York thought he
might safely be trusted to fill his place while he was away, and he was so
clever and honest that no one else seemed so well fitted for
it. It was now early in April, and the family was expected home sometime in May.
The light brown was to be fresh done up, and as Colonel blanty was obliged to
return to his regiment it was arranged that Smith would drive him to the town
in it, and ride back; for this purpose he took the saddle
with him, and I was chosen for the journey. At the station the colonel put
some money into Smith's hand and bid him goodbye saying, “Take care of your young
mistress Ruben and don't let Black OST to be hacked about by any random young
prig that wants to ride him— —keep him for the lady.” We left the carriage at the maker
and Smith rode me to the White Lion, and ordered the Hustler to feed me well, and
have me ready for him at 4:00 A nail in one of my front shoes had
started as I came along, but the hosler did not notice it till just about
4:00 Smith did not come into the yard till 5: and then he said he should not
leave till 600 as he had met with some old friends. The man then told him of the
nail, and asked if he should have the shoe looked to. “No,” said Smith, “that will
be all right until we get home.” He spoke in a very loud off hand
way, and I thought it very unlike him not to see about the shoe, as he was
generally wonderfully particular about loose nails in our
shoes. He did not come at 600 nor 7 nor 8
and it was nearly 9:00 before he called
for me, and then it was with a loud, rough
voice. He seemed in a very bad temper, and abused the Hustler though I could not tell what
four The landlord stood at the door and said, “Have a care, Mr. Smith!” but he
answered angrily with an oath; and almost before he was out of the town he began
to gallop, frequently giving me a sharp cut with his whip, though I was going at full
speed. The moon had not yet risen, and it was very dark. The roads were stony,
having been recently mended; going over them at this pace, my shoe became looser,
and as we neared the turnpike gate it came off. If Smith had been in his right
senses he would have been sensible of something wrong in my pace, but was too drunk to
notice. Beyond the turnpike was a long piece of road, upon which fresh stones
had just been laid— —large sharp stones, over which no horse could be driven
quickly without risk of danger. Over this road, with one shoe gone,
I was forced to gallop at my utmost speed, my rider meanwhile cutting into me
with his whip, and with wild curses urging me to go still faster. Of course
my shoeless foot suffered dreadfully; the hoof was broken and split down to the
very quick, and the inside was terribly cut by the sharpness of the
stones. This could not go on; no horse could keep his footing under such
circumstances; the pain was too great. I stumbled, and fell with violence on both
my knees. Smith was flung off by my fall,
and, owing to the speed I was going at, he must have fallen with great
force. I soon recovered my feet and limped to the side of the road, where it
was free from stones. The moon had just risen above the
hedge, and by its light I could see Smith lying a few yards beyond me. He did not
rise; he made one slight effort to do so, and then there was a heavy
groan. I could have groaned, too, for I was suffering intense pain both from my feet
and knees; but horses he used to bear their pain in silence. I uttered no sound,
but I stood there and listened. One more heavy groan from Smith;
but though he now lay in the full moonlight I could see no
motion. I could do nothing for him nor myself, but, oh! how I listened for the
sound of horse, or wheels, or footsteps! The road was not much
frequented, and at this time of the night we might stay for hours before help came to
us. I stood watching and listening. It was a calm, sweet April
night; there were no sounds but if a few low notes of a nightingale, and nothing
moved but the white clouds near the moon and a brown owl that flitted over the
hedge. It made me think of the summer nights long ago, when I used to lie
beside my mother in the green pleasant meadow at Farmer
graay end of chapter